Guide to the Dorothy Porter Wesley Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Series III. Research Files, 1847-2004
  - Remond Family Research Papers
    - Remond Family Papers
      - Amy Matilda Remond, Undated (Box 227, Folder 2115)
      - John Remond deeds, illustrations, and notes, Circa 1947-1991 (Box 227, Folder 2116-2122)
      - John Remond deeds, illustrations, and notes, Circa 1947-1991 (Box 228, Folder 2123-2129)
      - Lizzie M. Remond, 1868, Undated (Box 229, Folder 2130)
      - Maritchia Jaun Remond, Undated (Box 229, Folder 2131)
      - Nancy Remond, Undated (Box 229, Folder 2132)
      - Susan H. Remond, 1993- (Box 229, Folder 2133)
      - James Lee Sherman, Undated (Box 229, Folder 2134)
      - Sarah Parker Remond Lee Sherman, Undated (Box 229, Folder 2135)
    - General Research Files, Undated
      - Annual Report of the Edinburgh Ladies' Emancipation Society, 1854-1862, Undated (Box 229, Folder 2136)
      - Anti-Slavery Issues of the 1850s, Undated (Box 229, Folder 2137)
      - "The Black Leadership Class and Education in Antebellum Boston" by Arthur O. White, 1973- (Box 229, Folder 2138)
      - "The Black Putnams of Charlotte Forten's Journal" by Gloria Oden, 1990- (Box 229, Folder 2139)
      - Boston Negroes, Undated (Box 229, Folder 2140)
      - Broadsides, Undated (Box 229, Folder 2141)
      - Civil War articles on colored troops, 2001- (Box 229, Folder 2142)
      - The Colored American Magazine (copy), 1903- (Box 229, Folder 2143)
      - Colored Regiments, 2001- (Box 229, Folder 2144)
      - Curacao, Circa 1971-1991 (Box 230, Folder 2145-2148)
      - Curacao, 1971-1991 (Box 277 (Oversize), Folder 2569)
      - East Indian Marine Hall, Circa 1976 (Box 230, Folder 2149)
      - Essex Institute Historical Collections, catalogs, 1990- (Box 230, Folder 2150)
      - George Downing, Undated (Box 230, Folder 2151)
      - Illustrations, 1971-1988 (Box 230, Folder 2152)
      - Indexes, Undated (Box 230, Folder 2153)
      - James Wormley, 1993- (Box 230, Folder 2154)
      - Lewis Hayden, Undated (Box 230, Folder 2155)
      - Lectures, Undated (Box 277 (Oversize), Folder 2570)
      - List of free black heads of families, 1790, 1973- (Box 231, Folder 2156)
      - Maps and menus, Circa 1962-1972 (Box 231, Folder 2157)
      - Oversize, Undated (Box 277 (Oversize), Folder 2571)
      - Memories of a hundred years by Edward Everett Hale, Circa 1900 (Box 231, Folder 2158)
      - Ministers without Portfolios by Benjamin Quarles, 1954- (Box 231, Folder 2159)
      - The New England Anti-Slavery: Pioneer Abolition Organization Society by Roman J. Zorn, 1957- (Box 231, Folder 2160)
      - The Non-Slaveholder edited and published by Abm. L. Pennock, Samuel Rhoads and Geo. W. Taylor (Original), 1847- (Box 231, Folder 2161)
      - "Our Exemplars" by Matthew Davenport Hill (copy), 1861- (Box 231, Folder 2162)
      - People of color in Salem, Undated (Box 231, Folder 2163)
      - Po Harvey disks, Circa 1988-1990 (Box 231, Folder 2164)
      - Real estate (notes), 1967- (Box 231, Folder 2165)
      - Remarks On Slavery, 1806, 1970- (Box 231, Folder 2166)
      - Empty, Undated (Box 231, Folder 2167)
      - Report of the Committee of the Edinburgh Ladies Emancipation Society, 1864, 1967- (Box 231, Folder 2168)
      - Report on the Sundry Petitions Respecting Distinctions of Color, Petitions, 1839 (copy) (Box 231, Folder 2169)
      - Rescue of the Shadrock, 1851, 1897- (Box 231, Folder 2170)
      - Salem articles (copies), 1959- (Box 231, Folder 2171)
      - Scraps of African Methodist Episcopal history by Reverend James A. Handy (copy), Undated (Box 231, Folder 2172)
      - Sketches of Places and People Abroad by William Wells Brown (copy), 1855- (Box 231, Folder 2173)
      - Streets (notes), Undated (Box 231, Folder 2174)
      - Travel, 1980-1988 (Box 231, Folder 2175)
      - Travel, 1976-1988 (Box 278 (Oversize), Folder 2572)
      - Underground railroads, 1933-1971 (Box 231, Folder 2176)
      - Vital Statistics-Salem (copies), 1918-1925 (Box 231, Folder 2177)
      - William Bentley, diary (notes), Undated (Box 231, Folder 2178)
      - William Bentley, diary (notes), Undated (Box 232, Folder 2179)
      - Notes, Circa 1967-1995 (Box 232, Folder 2180-2184)
      - Notes, Circa 1967-1995 (Box 233, Folder 2185-2190)
      - Notes, Circa 1967-1995 (Box 234, Folder 2191-2194)
      - Notes, 1968-1989 (Box 278 (Oversize), Folder 2573)
      - Clippings, Circa 1889-1995 (Box 234, Folder 2195)
      - Clippings, 1968-1969 (Box 278 (Oversize), Folder 2574)
      - Publications, Circa 1938-1994 (Box 234, Folder 2196)
      - Publications, Circa 1938-1994 (Box 235, Folder 2197-2201)
      - Publications, Circa 1938-1994 (Box 236, Folder 2202-2207)
      - Publications, Circa 1938-1994 (Box 237, Folder 2208-2210)
      - Publications, Circa 1938-1994 (Box 238, Folder 2211-2217)
    - Sarah Parker Remond research files
      - Correspondence, (copies), 1857-1897 (Box 239, Folder 2218-2220)
      - African Americans in Europe, Circa 1977 (Box 239, Folder 2221)
      - African Meeting House, 1979- (Box 239, Folder 2222)
      - American Anti-Slavery Society, Circa 1990 (Box 239, Folder 2223)
      - Anthony Trollope, Undated (Box 239, Folder 2224)
      - Anti-Slavery Advocate, Circa 1858 (Box 239, Folder 2225-2226)
      - Anti-Slavery Convention, Undated (Box 239, Folder 2227)
      - Anti-Slavery Meetings in Salem (notes), Undated (Box 239, Folder 2228)
      - Anti-Slavery pamphlets (copies), 1864- (Box 240, Folder 2229)
      - Anti-Slavery reporter, 1827-1851, 1967- (Box 240, Folder 2230)
      - Artifacts in Essex Museum, Undated (Box 240, Folder 2231)
      - Aubrey House, Undated (Box 240, Folder 2232)
      - Autobiography of Sarah Parker Remond (excerpt, copies), 1861- (Box 240, Folder 2233)
      - Bowditch Papers Guide Essex Institute in Salem, Undated (Box 240, Folder 2234)
      - British for Anti-Slavery Society, 1859- (Box 240, Folder 2235)
      - British Isles maps, 1976-1988 (Box 240, Folder 2236)
      - Charlotte Forten, 1976-1988 (Box 240, Folder 2237)
      - Chase Family Letters (excerpt copies), 1975-1988 (Box 240, Folder 2238)
      - Churches, Undated (Box 240, Folder 2239)
      - Douglas Monthly, (copies), 1859- (Box 240, Folder 2240)
      - Early authors, Undated (Box 240, Folder 2241)
      - Edinburgh National Library, Scotland, Undated (Box 240, Folder 2242)
      - Elizabeth Blackwell notes, Undated (Box 241, Folder 2243)
      - England, 1974- (Box 241, Folder 2244)
      - Essex Institute, 1983- (Box 241, Folder 2245)
      - Ethiopia, (poem) By a lady of color from London empire, (copy), 1855- (Box 241, Folder 2246)
      - Female Salem Anti-Slavery Society (copies), 1839-1853 (Box 241, Folder 2247)
      - Fred Scott Decision, Undated (Box 241, Folder 2248)
      - Frederick Douglass and the Remonds, Circa 1968 (Box 241, Folder 2249)
      - Fugitive slave stories, Undated (Box 241, Folder 2250)
      - Giuseppe Garibaldi, Circa 1983 (Box 241, Folder 2251)
      - Glasgow Mitchell Library, Undated (Box 241, Folder 2252)
      - Harmony Grove Cemetary, 1960-1989 (Box 241, Folder 2253)
      - Harriet Beecher Stowe, 1976- (Box 241, Folder 2254)
      - Harriett Beecher Stowe, 1976- (Box 278 (Oversize), Folder 2575)
      - Howard Athenaeum Case, 1835, Undated (Box 241, Folder 2255)
      - Illustrations, Undated (Box 278 (Oversize), Folder 2576)
      - Hymns Sung (copy), 1835- (Box 241, Folder 2256)
      - Illustrations, Circa 1975-1989 (Box 242, Folder 2257)
      - Illustrations, 1975-1992 (Box 278 (Oversize), Folder 2577)
      - Indexes, 1991- (Box 242, Folder 2258)
      - Italy, Circa 1968-1994 (Box 242, Folder 2259-2259a)
      - Italy, 1994- (Box 278 (Oversize), Folder 2578)
      - John Bishop Eslin, Undated (Box 242, Folder 2260)
      - Jurors, Undated (Box 242, Folder 2261)
      - Ladies College, Undated (Box 242, Folder 2262)
      - Ladies Society for the Aid of Fugitive Slaves in England, Undated (Box 242, Folder 2263)
      - Lectures, Circa 1974
        - Lecture Schedules (Box 242, Folder 2264)
        - England
          - Bristol (Box 242, Folder 2265)
            - Oversize, 1859- (Box 278 (Oversize), Folder 2579)
          - Chesterfield (Box 243, Folder 2266)
          - Finsbury (Box 243, Folder 2267)
          - Halifax (Box 243, Folder 2268)
          - Leeds (Box 243, Folder 2269)
          - Liverpool (Box 243, Folder 2270)
          - London (Box 243, Folder 2271)
          - Manchester (Box 243, Folder 2272)
          - Penketh (Box 243, Folder 2273)
          - Ulverston (Box 243, Folder 2274)
          - Wakefield (Box 243, Folder 2275)
          - Warrington (Box 243, Folder 2276-2277)
            - Oversize (Box 278 (Oversize), Folder 2580)
        - Ireland
          - Clonmel (Box 243, Folder 2278)
          - Cork (Box 243, Folder 2279)
          - Dublin (Box 244, Folder 2280)
          - Waterford (Box 244, Folder 2281)
        - Scotland
          - Dumfries (Box 244, Folder 2282)
          - Edinburgh (Box 244, Folder 2283)
        - Notes (Box 244, Folder 2284-2286)
        - Notes (Box 245, Folder 2287)
      - The Liberator, copies of clippings and notes, Circa 1832-1859 (Box 245, Folder 2288-2290)
      - The Liberator, copies of clippings and notes, 1858-1859 (Box 278 (Oversize), Folder 2581)
      - Literary Societies, Undated (Box 245, Folder 2291)
      - Lola Montez, Undated (Box 245, Folder 2292)
      - London (general notes), 1972- (Box 245, Folder 2293)
      - London Emancipation Committee, 1859, Circa 1972 (Box 245, Folder 2294)
      - Maps of the United Kingdom, Undated (Box 245, Folder 2295)
      - Mary Lenox Estate, Undated (Box 245, Folder 2296)
      - Massachusetts Anti-Slavery Society, Undated (Box 245, Folder 2297)
      - Empty, Undated (Box 245, Folder 2298)
      - National Anti-Slavery Bazaars, Undated (Box 245, Folder 2299)
      - National Anti-Slavery Standard (copies), Circa 1845-1868 (Box 245, Folder 2300)
      - Negroes and Anglo-Africans as Freedmen and Soldiers compiled by Sarah Parker Remond, 1864 (copy) (Box 245, Folder 2301)
      - New England Anti-Slavery Convention, Undated (Box 246, Folder 2302)
      - New York Colonization Journal, 1859- (Box 246, Folder 2303)
      - Passport data, Circa 1981 (Box 246, Folder 2304)
      - Pennsylvania Anti-Slavery Fair, Undated (Box 246, Folder 2305)
      - Philadelphia Female Anti-Slavery Society, 1857, Circa 1987 (Box 246, Folder 2306)
      - Philadelphia Women's Association (copies), Undated (Box 246, Folder 2307)
      - The Red Lodge, Undated (Box 246, Folder 2308)
      - Remond family grave site, 1989- (Box 246, Folder 2309)
      - Reverend Samuel Joseph May, Undated (Box 246, Folder 2310)
      - Richard D. Webb (1854-1859), Undated (Box 246, Folder 2311)
      - Salem Charitable Mechanic Association, Undated (Box 246, Folder 2312)
      - Salem-Hawthorne, 1804-1864, 1988-1992 (Box 246, Folder 2313)
      - Salem Female Anti-Slavery Society, 1990- (Box 246, Folder 2314)
      - Salem Martine National Historic Site, 1976-1987 (Box 246, Folder 2315)
      - Salem's early slave history, 1985- (Box 247, Folder 2316)
      - Samuel May, 1973- (Box 247, Folder 2317)
      - Samuel R. Ward, 1976- (Box 247, Folder 2318)
      - Sardinia, 1986-1987 (Box 247, Folder 2319)
      - Sardinia, 1978- (Box 278 (Oversize), Folder 2582)
      - Ships, Undated (Box 247, Folder 2320)
      - Susan B. Anthony, 1968- (Box 247, Folder 2321)
      - Susan Paul, Circa 1833-1837 (Box 247, Folder 2322)
      - Trip to Rome, Italy (photos), Circa 1967-1990 (Box 247, Folder 2323-2325)
      - Wendell Phillips on Crispus Attucks, 1849- (Box 248, Folder 2326)
      - William Hull, Undated (Box 248, Folder 2327)
      - Willliam Wells Brown, 1979- (Box 248, Folder 2328-2329)
      - William P. Powell, Circa 1973 (Box 248, Folder 2330)
      - Women professors, Circa 1963-1981 (Box 248, Folder 2331)
      - Notes, Circa 1962-1992 (Box 248, Folder 2332-2333)
      - Notes, Circa 1962-1992 (Box 249, Folder 2334-2340)
      - Notes, Circa 1962-1992 (Box 250, Folder 2341-2343)
      - Notes, 1983-1992 (Box 278 (Oversize), Folder 2583)
      - Ephemera, 1986- (Box 278 (Oversize), Folder 2584)
    - Charles Lenox Remond research files
      - Amy M. Remond, Undated (Box 251, Folder 2344)
      - Anti-Slavery Women of Pawtucket, Rhode Island, Undated (Box 251, Folder 2345)
      - Articles about Charles Remond, Circa 1975-1988 (Box 251, Folder 2346-2348)
      - Catalogue calendar and Bibliography of the Collections, 1990- (Box 251, Folder 2349)
      - Charles Remond Jr. 1861-1881, Undated (Box 251, Folder 2350)
      - Chronology, Undated (Box 251, Folder 2351-2352)
      - Elizabeth M. Remond, Circa 1988 (Box 252, Folder 2353)
      - Ellen and William Craft, 1965-1967 (Box 252, Folder 2354)
      - George T. Downing, Undated (Box 252, Folder 2355)
      - House and Land, Undated (Box 252, Folder 2356)
      - Illustrations, 1989- (Box 252, Folder 2357)
      - Joshua B. Smith, 1974- (Box 252, Folder 2358)
      - Letters 1839-1843 (copies), Circa 1967 (Box 252, Folder 2359-2363)
        - Oversize (copies), Circa 1839-1843 (Box 279, Folder 2587-2588)
      - The Liberator (copies), Undated (Box 253, Folder 2364-2365)
      - National Anti-Slavery Standard (copies), Circa 1840-1859 (Box 253, Folder 2366)
        - Oversize (copies), Circa 1857 (Box 278 (Oversize), Folder 2585)
      - Newspaper file photocopies (oversize), Circa 1844-1858 (Box 280, Folder 2589-2590b)
      - North Star (copies), Circa 1850 (Box 253, Folder 2367)
      - Photographs, Circa 1972 (Box 253, Folder 2368)
      - Probate Records, Undated (Box 253, Folder 2369)
      - Publications, Circa 1949-1987 (Box 253, Folder 2370-2372)
      - References to be checked, Undated (Box 254, Folder 2374)
      - Richard Cobden (photograph), Undated (Box 254, Folder 2375)
      - Salem publications, Circa 1882-1896 (Box 254, Folder 2376-2377)
      - Speeches (1854-1867), Circa 1972-1978 (Box 255, Folder 2378-2379)
      - Thomas Cole, Undated (Box 255, Folder 2380)
      - United States Lectures 1856-1858, Circa 1856-1858 (Box 255, Folder 2381)
      - Wendall Phillips Remond, Undated (Box 255, Folder 2382)
      - William Lloyd Garrison, 1978- (Box 255, Folder 2383)
      - Notes, Circa 1970-1978 (Box 255, Folder 2384-2386)
      - Notes, Circa 1970-1978 (Box 256, Folder 2387-2388)
        - Clippings (oversize), 1974-1983 (Box 278 (Oversize), Folder 2586)
  - William Cooper Nell Research Files
    The William Cooper Nell Research Files consists of writings and materials on abolitionist William Cooper Nell by Dorothy Porter Wesley, her second husband Charles Harris Wesley, and daughter Constance Porter Uzelac. Research for the bibliography William Cooper Nell, Nineteenth-Century African American Abolitionist, Historian, Integrationist: Selected Writings 1832-1874 (2002) is contained in this series.
    - Charles Harris Wesley Writings on William Cooper Nell
      - Correspondence on William Cooper Nell research to and from Charles Harris Wesley, 1978- (Box 256, Folder 2389)
      - Biographical information, Circa 1974-1994 (Box 256, Folder 2390)
      - Crispus Attucks 1852-1863, 1991- (Box 256, Folder 2391)
      - Drafts, Chapters 1-3, Circa 1976-1987 (Box 256, Folder 2392-2393)
      - Notes on William Cooper Nell, Circa 1976-1978 (Box 256, Folder 2394-2395)
      - Notes on William Cooper Nell, Circa 1976-1978 (Box 257, Folder 2396-2397)
      - Notes (general), Circa 1976-1987 (Box 257, Folder 2398-2400)
    - Dorothy Porter Wesley Writings on William Cooper Nell
      - Correspondence on William Cooper Nell research to and from Dorothy Porter Wesley and Constance Porter Uzelac, 1979-2001 (Box 258, Folder 2401)
      - Chapter outlines, 1991-2001 (Box 258, Folder 2402)
      - Footnotes, 1995- (Box 258, Folder 2403)
      - William Cooper Nell 1816-1874, Introduction (draft), 1994-1995 (Box 258, Folder 2404)
      - William Cooper Nell: Integration vs. Seperation The Black Dilenmma (draft), 1992- (Box 258, Folder 2405)
    - General Research Files
      - Adelphic Union Library Association Institute, 1838-1840, Undated (Box 259, Folder 2406)
      - Advertisements, 1990-1993 (Box 259, Folder 2407)
      - Amos Germon Beman and Jehiel C. Beman, 1937-1992 (Box 259, Folder 2408)
      - Amy Kirby Post, biographical information, 1978-1990 (Box 259, Folder 2409)
      - Anderson Auction Catalogue 1905, 1995- (Box 259, Folder 2410)
      - Anti-Slavery Literature (copies), Circa 1854-1859 (Box 259, Folder 2411)
      - Bibliographies, Undated (Box 259, Folder 2412)
      - Biographical information, 1951-1994 (Box 259, Folder 2413-2414)
      - Biography notes, Circa 1994 (Box 259, Folder 2415)
      - Biography notes, 1994- (Box 281 (Oversize), Folder 2591)
      - Black Abolitionist Papers, 1961-1983 (Box 259, Folder 2416)
      - Book Cover, 2002- (Box 259, Folder 2417)
      - Boston Directories (copies), Circa 1813-1818 (Box 259, Folder 2418)
      - Boston Massacre (copy), 1858- (Box 259, Folder 2419)
      - Boston Newspapers to be checked, 1994- (Box 259, Folder 2420)
      - Checklists, 1994- (Box 260, Folder 2421)
      - Colored National Convention (copies), Circa 1855-1856 (Box 260, Folder 2422)
      - Colored Patriots the American Revolutionary (copies), Circa 1855-1864 (Box 260, Folder 2423)
      - Crispus Attucks Celebration, 1865-1866, 2004- (Box 260, Folder 2424)
      - Death Certificates, 1874, 1977- (Box 260, Folder 2425)
      - Donald Jacobs, 1970-1971 (Box 260, Folder 2426)
      - Elijah William Smith, 1902- (Box 260, Folder 2427)
      - Employment Agency (copies of clippings), Circa 1843-1859 (Box 260, Folder 2428)
      - Facts, Figures and Players, Undated (Box 260, Folder 2429)
      - Flags of America, 1991- (Box 260, Folder 2430)
      - Forest Hill Cemetary, 1978-1989 (Box 260, Folder 2431)
      - Format Policies and Procedures, Undated (Box 260, Folder 2432)
      - Frances Ames, 1860, 1993- (Box 260, Folder 2433)
      - Frances Harper, Undated (Box 260, Folder 2434)
      - Frederick Douglass, 1976-1990 (Box 260, Folder 2435)
      - Frederick Douglass, 1990- (Box 281 (Oversize), Folder 2592)
      - Fugitive Slave Act of 1850-1851, Circa 1987 (Box 260, Folder 2436)
      - George Lowther, 1990-1991 (Box 260, Folder 2437)
      - Gerrit Smith Collection, Undated (Box 260, Folder 2438)
      - George W. Forbes, Undated (Box 260, Folder 2439)
      - Grave marker for William Cooper Nell, 1989- (Box 261, Folder 2440-2441)
      - Harper's Ferry, Undated (Box 261, Folder 2442)
      - Harriet Ann Nell, Undated (Box 261, Folder 2443)
      - Illustrations, 1991-1998 (Box 261, Folder 2444-2445)
      - Illustrations, Circa 1991-1998 (Box 281 (Oversize), Folder 2593)
      - Integration vs. Seperation: William Cooper Nell's Role in the Struggle for Equality by Dorothy Porter Wesley, 1991- (Box 261, Folder 2446)
      - Jeremiah Sanderson, Circa 1952-1968 (Box 261, Folder 2447)
      - The Liberator, copies of clippings and notes, Circa 1859-1995 (Box 261, Folder 2448)
      - The Liberator, copies of clippings and notes, Circa 1859-1995 (Box 262, Folder 2449-2451)
      - Louisa Gray (copies of letters), 1865- (Box 262, Folder 2452)
      - Madame Carteaux Bannister, Undated (Box 262, Folder 2453)
      - Mary C. Munroe scrapbook (copy clippings), Undated (Box 262, Folder 2454)
      - Mirror of Liberty, 1838 (copy), Circa 1940 (Box 262, Folder 2455)
      - Mirror of Liberty, 1838 (copy) (Box 281 (Oversize), Folder 2594)
      - National Antislavery Standard, 1869, 1976- (Box 262, Folder 2456)
      - National Archives and Records Administration, 1973- (Box 262, Folder 2457)
      - Negatives, Undated (Box 262, Folder 2458)
      - North Star, Undated (Box 262, Folder 2459)
      - Property Qualifications, 2004- (Box 262, Folder 2460)
      - Publications, 1938-1968 (Box 263, Folder 2461-2465)
      - Public conveyances, discrimination, 1993- (Box 263, Folder 2466)
      - Ripley Indexes, 1991- (Box 263, Folder 2467)
      - Sarah Roberts Case
        - African Meeting House, 1979- (Box 264, Folder 2468)
        - Case Comments, 1979- (Box 264, Folder 2469-2470)
        - Reports, 1979- (Box 264, Folder 2471)
        - Empty, Undated (Box 264, Folder 2472-2473)
        - Script, 1979-1981 (Box 264, Folder 2474-2476)
        - Notes, 1979-1981 (Box 265, Folder 2477)
      - Services of Colored Americans in 1776-1812, Undated (Box 265, Folder 2478)
      - Smith School, 1975- (Box 265, Folder 2479)
      - Theodore Parker, Undated (Box 265, Folder 2480)
      - Thomas Jennings, Undated (Box 265, Folder 2481)
      - Vigilance Committtee, Undated (Box 265, Folder 2482)
      - Weekly Anglo-African and Anglo-African Magazine excerpts, Undated (Box 265, Folder 2483)
      - Wendell Phillips (copies of clippings), 1866- (Box 265, Folder 2484)
      - Wendell Phillips (original Anti-slavery standard clippings), 1868- (Box 281 (Oversize), Folder 2595)
      - Will of Jesse Nell, 1979- (Box 265, Folder 2485)
      - William Cooper Nell clippings, copies of speeches, memorandum and correspondence, Circa 1830-1874 (Box 265, Folder 2486-2488)
      - William Cooper Nell clippings, copies of speeches, memorandum and correspondence, Circa 1830-1874 (Box 266, Folder 2489-2493)
      - William Cooper Nell clippings, copies of speeches, memorandum and correspondence, Circa 1830-1874 (Box 267, Folder 2494-2499)
      - William Cooper Nell clippings, copies of speeches, memorandum and correspondence, Circa 1830-1874 (Box 268, Folder 2500-2504)
      - William Cooper Nell clippings, copies of speeches, memorandum and correspondence, Circa 1830-1874 (Box 269, Folder 2505-2510)
      - William Cooper Nell clippings, copies of speeches, memorandum and correspondence, Circa 1830-1874 (Box 270, Folder 2511-2514)
      - William Cooper Nell clippings, copies of speeches, memorandum and correspondence, Circa 1830-1874 (Box 271, Folder 2515-2519)
      - William Cooper Nell clippings, copies of speeches, memorandum and correspondence, Circa 1830-1874 (Box 272, Folder 2520-2522)
      - Notes, Circa 1974-2001 (Box 272, Folder 2523-2525)
      - Notes, Circa 1974-2001 (Box 273, Folder 2526-2532)
      - Notes, 1992-1993 (Box 281 (Oversize), Folder 2596)
      - General clippings, 1854-1976 (Box 281 (Oversize), Folder 2597)
      - Clippings, copies by or about William Cooper Nell, Circa 1853 (Box 282, Folder 2598-2600c)
- Series IV. Personal Papers
  Personal Papers includes photographs, financial documents and ephemera belonging to Dorothy Porter Wesley, Constance Porter Uzelac, James Amos Porter, Charles Harris Wesley, and other extended family members. Dorothy Porter Wesley received personal items from her parents and siblings upon their deaths including tennis records, a memoir and records documenting the tennis career of Wesley's mother, Roberta (Bertha) Ball Burnett, and deeds and journals from her sisters Leonie Burnett Harper and Alice Taylor. Other items include original commencement records from Howard University School of Medicine and Lincoln University respectively belonging to Wesley's father Hayes Joseph Burnett and brother Hayes Burnett II. Wesley was also a beneficiary of the estate belonging to Lula V. Allan and Bertha Allan, who were librarians, teachers and mentors to Wesley at Miner Normal School. The materials belonging to Lula and Bertha Allan include third party correspondence, wills, photographs and ephemera.
  Personal Papers is organized into five subseries: General Personal Papers belonging to Dorothy Porter Wesley; Financial records; Ephemera; Family Papers; and Lula and Bertha Allan papers.
  - General Personal Papers of Dorothy Porter Welsey
    - Addresses and Business Cards, Circa 1935-1995 (Box 283, Folder 2600-2605)